Hello friends,
welcome to the channel. In today's video, we are going to
analyze the shares of ICI Lombard. We will
also study the technical chart of what will be the target price of the share and
we are also going to discuss the breakout given by the company.
So this video is very
informative. If we
talk about the stock, then the market
capitalization of ICICI Lombard is Rs 71000 crore
and right now
this stock is trading at Rs 40.7. Its 52
week high is
14.92 and its 52 week low is
1049.
If we look at the fundamentals of the company, then first of all, if
we talk about profit and loss, then the company has
generated the highest ever net profit in the last year. The company has shown a net profit of Rs 1729 crore, which
means the
sales generated have also been the highest ever. The
operating profit in the year is also the highest ever.
So fundamentally, the company seems strong.
If we look at the quarter  If we look at it on a quarterly basis, the
sales figure is also the highest ever sales figure
in this quarter, in the previous quarter, the
company has shown the highest ever sales figures in September 2023, profit before
tax and profit after tax are also one of the
highest, so
I do not think there is any problem in investing in the company, so first of all
if we
talk about historical valuations, if
we talk about the median P of the historical valuation, then the
median P is and
if we look at FIRE first of all, the median P of
FIRE is 46.2 for five years and this company is
currently trading below the median P of
FIRE, right now the P ratio of the company is
around 41 and
its median P is 46,
by the way, in March 2023, this company touched the lowest
valuation, the historical valuation
lowest P is around 30 from
there  The company has already seen a significant rally, as
we can see in the charts.
If we look at the 10-year P/E, the
listing is not that old. It was
listed on October 17. So, if we
talk about the year P/E, the P/E
ratio is also median
P/E of 46. As I mentioned earlier,
Abhay Company is trading at P/E of 41. So,
here also the
company is available to us at a discount.
If we talk about the price
to book value, its median P/E
is 7.9 and the company is
currently trading at a P/E of around 6.3.
Here also we are
getting the company at a discount. We are
not buying it at the top. It is a good
thing that we should never buy a company near its 52-
week high or its highest valuation
because
we may have to stay
invested in it for a longer period of time.
If this stock falls from there, then if
we talk about the share holding
pattern of the company, the promoter has 48
ICICI Bank is
its promoter and FI has holding at 22,
FI has holding at 22,
DI has holding at 18.4 and the
general public has holding at 11,
so the holding of almost 89 to 90 is in
strong hands,
if we see, here the
share of FI was almost around 30, from
there they sold the share at almost 8
and it is seen that DI has purchased as much as FI has
sold,
if we talk about technical analysis, then
this company is seen showing
inverted head and shoulder pattern here, here a head has been formed,
sorry here a shoulder has been formed here, here a shoulder
and this is what we can see its formation
and here the company has given a break out,
here you can see
there is a shoulder here, the more the
shoulders here, the more it
consolidates.  There is more consolidation and the
breakout here is more, we mean
we can consider it more sustainable there, so let
me zoom it a little and show
you that the company has tried to give breakout here two or three times, once here, once
here and finally
we have seen the breakout of the company coming here
and it has also been confirmed by the next
candle,
so if we talk about its price target, then according to the
inverted head and shoulder pattern that is being formed,
if we talk
then a price target of 1750
is coming out here, friends, this is not any buy or sell
advice or anything, I recommend it, that
means I myself consider
it a good stock in my portfolio
and I have a good holding in it,
I myself am invested in it,
before investing you
must take help of your financial advice, so that's all in this video,
if you found this video informative
then do not forget to like the video and subscribe to the channel,
Jai
Hind